Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives, 1982-2001 MSS.231
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XI: Gay USA
  - 1994 Vol. XII
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 28 [Air date: 7/14/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0410 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0410)
      1. News Notes: 30 anti-gay assaults occur during Gay Games and Stonewall 25, which the city is denying happened. Giuliani's office number is displayed. Christine Gebby resigns. Three more athletes disqualified after using steroids during Gay Games. Dick Sargent's death is announced. Brett Easton Ellis' sexuality is questioned. Viewers are warned against going to the Caiman Islands.
      2. Karen Burstein, candidate for New York State Attorney General is interviewed.
      3. Vernal Scott introduces regular reports from England. A pride march is shown in London.
      4. California football finalist game shown. Team LA vs LA Quakes. Jim Buzinski of Team LA, Lynn Lewis of Team NY interviewed.
      5. Lavender Health: Ken Togo, who opened the first clinic for gay men and lesbians in Japan, and is an acclaimed LBGT figure there, is interviewed. Togo's stage performance is shown.
      6. Special Edition of Naming Names, The GLAAD Report Card on Stonewall 25, which covers the best and worst coverage of Gay Games IV and Stonewall 25. Top honors go to New York Newsday, The New York Times, CBS Evening News, News 4 NY, and New York 1. Dunce caps go to The New York Post, Sports Illustrated, ABC News, Channel 5 News at 10, and Good Day New York.
      7. The Lambda Update: Beatrice Dohrn introduces the broadcast. Lou Maletta interviews Evan Wolfson about the same sex equal rights case in Hawaii. Patrick Lagon and Joe Mellio, plaintiffs in the case, are interviewed as well. Nina Baehr and Genora Dancel, Barbara Warkas and Carol Lam are interviewed as well.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 29 [Air date: 7/21/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0411 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0411)
      NOTES: New set for opening segment.
      1. News Notes: Clinton wants Tracy Thorne thrown out of NAVY. Olympic committee considering moving volleyball game from outside of Cobb County. Boy Scouts lose funding from United Way. Barry Goldwater endorses gay rights. Viewers are encouraged to call the NYC School Chancellor to demand that William Andrews be fired after remarks that gays were "coming for your children". Gay book store in Cincinnati is raided by police for carrying a copy of "Salo: 120 Days of Sodom". A demonstration against George Pataki is announced.
      2. Arnie Kantrowitz of the Gay Activists Alliance speaks.
      3. Gay Games IV coverage: David Mitchell covers martial arts. Jesse Garcia covers water polo finals. Ed Dixon covers bowling.
      4. Lavender Health: Tuberculosis short film. Dr. Thomas Freeden, director of Tuberculosis Control is interviewed.
      5. Naming Names: The Tonight Show features its first openly gay comedian, Bob Smith. Viewers are encouraged to write to Bill Royce, co-producer of The Tonight Show.
      6. Interview with Patricia Nell Warren, author of Harlan's Race.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 30 [Air date: 7/28/1994], July 1994; ID: 231.0412 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0412)
      1. News Notes: Rush Limbaugh fired as Florida Citrus spokesman. Military banned from recruiting at University of Connecticut Law School. Wigstock in danger of not happening. Cardinal O'Connor announces he will close every Catholic hospital in the city if abortion becomes part of national health care reform. Filming is beginning on The Celluloid Closet. 'The Ramrod Killer' is trying to get out of psychiatric care. Harvey Firestein headlines CBS sitcom. Sue Simmons reveals accidentally that she is a lesbian.
      2. At the Sheraton New York, multi-million dollar fundraiser for George Pataki, who says he is against gay rights. Ann Northrup and Senator Al D'Amato interviewed. George Pataki speaks to reporters, when Andy Humm tries to ask a question, an activist shouts "Pataki is a bigot!". Rudy Washington, commissioner, Howard Koeppel (a gay Republican), and Betsy McCaughey are interviewed. Caroline Quartararo, Pataki's press secretary is interviewed and angrily demands Humm turn the camera off.
      3. London's memorial quilt and The Names Project UK is covered. Vernal Scott reports from London and tours the quilt and some of the exhibits around it.
      4. Lavender Health: Harm reduction on a day to day basis. Howard Josepher speaks. Donna La Loma,
      5. Larry Kramer is interviewed.
      6. Naming Names: Woodstock 94 hosts Shabba Ranks, who has made homophobic statements. Viewers are encouraged to write to Michael Lang of Woodstock Ventures to get Ranks pulled.
      7. Lambda Update: Kevin Cathcart introduces Suzanne B. Goldberg, discussing anti-gay initiatives.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 31 [Air date: 8/4/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0413 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0413)
      1. News Notes: Congress will have a hearing on work discrimination against gays and lesbians. Cobb County is covered in an article in the New York Times, 'A Suburban Eden Where the Right Rules'. Susan Sarandon endorses Tom Duane. Serial killer Gary Ray Bowles is sought in the south. Gay Games needs money to cover its loss. Norma McCorvey comes out.
      2. Matt Foreman of the Anti-Violence Project is interviewed and holds a town meeting on police misconduct and abuse, and the Rueben Diaz controversy. Edward Silver, Ruth Messigner, and Deborah Glick speak.
      3. Lavender Health: Closing ceremony of Gay Games IV at Yankee Stadium with Dan Myers. Edna Spring, Jose Badue, Jim Frawley, Reggie Snowdon, and Gwinn Leggis interviewed.
      4. Angelica Rovira and Mark E. Seitelman are interviewed. Rovira The audio on this segment is very bad at the start of the interview. Rovira claims she was assaulted by Luis Solard (sp?) of the school board.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert (formerly Naming Names): American Express advertises to gay and lesbians. Viewers are encouraged to write to Harvey Golub of American Express. An update states that the Olympic committee has pulled the volleyball event from Cobb County.
      6. Lee Sharmat interviews Judy Nelson, host of In the Life.
      7. Footage from the Powerlifting event of Gay Games IV. Tom Tudesco is interviewed.
      COMMERCIAL: Teleconference from The International AIDS Conference
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 32 [Air date: 8/11/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0414 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0414)
      1. News Notes: Because Andy Humm had knee surgery, News Notes is held from Humm's apartment bed. Patsy Flemming is interim AIDS czar. Greenburg, New York is considering benefits for gay and lesbian couples. Tom Duane is having a fundraiser. A broadcast about a botched 911 response from NY1 featuring Matt Foreman and Tom Duane is shown. GLAAD protests anti-gay t-shirts being sold on the Jersey Shore, with the support of the New Jersey governor. Liam Neeson is considered for the lead in an Oscar Wilde biopic by Mike Nichols.
      2. International AIDS Conference in Yokohama, Japan. A satellite feed from Japan of a roundtable conference is shown, taped off of a monitor with Closed Captioning turned on (the audience can be heard murmuring and coughing). Michael Saag is the only one identified by text. Dale Hogan provides an outro and interviews Brian Jankowsi of the Treatment Action Group.
      3. Lou Maletta interviews Richard Jones, intern on The Howard Stern Show, who is openly gay.
      COMMERCIAL: Speak to the Senate (a recent senate decision overwhelmingly ruled against 'gay education' in schools)
      4. Lavender Health: The US House and Senate pass a bill called the Elementary and Secondary Act, which featured an amendment introduced by Bob Smith and Jesse Helms prohibiting school districts from providing counseling to gay students or distributing material that deals with gay and lesbian issues, or making referrals to gay and lesbian organizations. From the Harvey Milk School, Maisha Uzuri James is interviewed.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Willard Scott endorses Cracker Barrel on The Today Show. Viewers are encouraged to write to The Today Show and tell them to stop endorsing Cracker Barrel.
      6. Lambda Update: Beatrice Dohrn discusses gays in the military. Footage from Donahue is shown.
      7. Andy Humm tries to unravel the bandage on his knee while the credits roll.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 33 [Air date: 8/18/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0415 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0415)
      1. News Notes: George Pataki gets a '100% approval rating' from Pat Robertson. Protests in Huntsville, Alabama over the Metropolitan Community Church, which accepts gays and lesbians as parishioners. Andrew Crispo leaves info on phone sex lines. Eve's Garden celebrates 25th anniversary. Under Giuliani, gay interest and human rights groups are being gutted. Gabriel Rotello attacks Christopher Lynn for endorsing Rueben Diaz. Cincinnati anti-gay measure is thrown out. The Catholic Church condemns the UN for endorsing condoms and sexual health.
      2. Woodstock 94 is covered. Lou Maletta interviews attendees. Some of Nine Inch Nails' concert is briefly shown.
      3. Highlights from GCN's debate with Jerry Nadler and Tom Duane. Its announced that the full 1-hour debate will appear on Out on Wednesdays, August 25th at 11pm.
      4. Lavender Health: Benjamin A Mojica of STD Control is interviewed.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: The Helms/Smith sponsored amendment which will cut funds to schools that 'advance the homosexual lifestyle' is covered. Viewers are encouraged to write to their congressmen; Sen Al D'amato for NY.
      6. Deborah Barsha in Newark, NY on the set of The Incredibly True Adventure of Two Girls in Love. Maria Maggenti, Dolly Hall, Lori E. Seid, and Mark Huisman are interviewed.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 34 [Air date: 8/25/1994], August 1994; ID: 231.0416 (Box 26, Media ID: 231.0416)
      1. News Notes: Urban Fitness is launched. A study reveals 20% of adults have gay impulses. In Tacoma, WA, the home of three gay roommates is targeted by vandals. Mayor Joseph Maranin in Connecticut wants to kill AIDS services. University of Wisconsin decides against domestic partner benefits. Nelson Thacker, who killed a gay man in Salt Lake City has his sentence reduced. Sierra Club offers straight and gay trips. Nebraska lesbian fighting to keep custody of son. Sharon Bottoms trying to get hearing in custody case. The New York Times runs a story on how hard of a sell gay movies are. Wigstock finds a host.
      2. The Morning Party. Jeff Richardson, and Nora Burns interviewed.
      3. Tom Duane interviewed. Duane and Ann Northrop speak.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: The Sony Video 1 board in Times Square refuses to run a gay PSA called 'Why not love?' The spot is shown. Viewers are encouraged to write to Sony.
      6. Lavender Health: Animated PSA about Hepatitis B and HIV. Joyce Dunmore is interviewed.
      7. Lambda Update: William A. Peters introduces the broadcast. Beatrice Dohrn speaks about Daniel Miller, a man in Pennsylvania fired from his job because he was gay.
      8. Wigstock 93 footage. Runs over the end credits as well.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 35 [Air date: 9/1/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0417 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0417)
      1. News Notes: Two TV specials on Martina Navratilova, who was just named as president of Women's Tennis Association. Rumor is that Gay Games is $1 million in debt. NY Times on Provincetown vacations. Giuliani still trying to gut AIDS Services. Tokyo hosts Pride March. Gay group marches in parallel with India Day parade. Four high school football stars are arrested in Texas over murder of a gay man. Nebraska lesbian wins custody of son. A Mississippi ambulance service leaves an AIDS patient to die on his porch; he didn't die and is now suing. Humm's mic keeps spiking during this segment.
      2. David Blanton, a new correspondent on GCN, is introduced. Blanton works for Vote Smart, and introduces the organization. Adelaide B. Elm of Vote Smart is interviewed over the phone.
      3. Steve Weinstein interviews photographer Carolyn Jones and Michael Liberatore, author of Living Proof: Courage in the Face of AIDS. A clip from Living Proof: HIV and the Pursuit of Happiness is shown.
      4. Damien Corboy, a former senate aide, is interviewed about the chances of a Democratic takeover of the house and senate.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Lifetime presents 1-hour biography of Martina Navratilova, making only a brief, matter-of-fact statement on her lesbianism. Viewers are encouraged to write to Lifetime.
      6. Dale Hogan reviews The Adventures of Priscilla: Queen of the Desert. A clip is shown.
      7. Lavender Health: Torrence Allen and D'Jeno Jean Romain are interviewed.
      8. Lady Bunny, organizer of Wigstock is interviewed.
      9. Lengthy outro from Humm and Sharmatt followed by another clip from Priscilla.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 36 [Air date: 9/8/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0418 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0418)
      1. News Notes: The New York Times runs an article that 1 in 5 people have had a homosexual attraction at some point in their life. Another NY Times article about gays saving inner cities. The death of Michael Peters and Walter Raine are announced. A man who believed AIDS could be passed through sneezing set out to murder Governer Cuomo and slit the throat of Francis Tarlton. Dr. Tusch, who ran Laser Medical Associates (advertised heavily on GCN), and had 49 malpractice counts against him, attempted suicide and relocated to Washington state. His medical license was never revoked. Dan Quayle considers running for president.
      2. Karen Burstein, candidate for Attorney General is interviewed.
      3. Tom Duane is interviewed.
      4. At Wigstock, Lou Maletta interviews Ruth Messinger about the upcoming primaries.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Andre Agassi makes homophobic statements, Nike continues to sponsor him. Viewers are encouraged to call Nike and demand Agassi either be removed or made to apologize.
      6. Lavender Health: Coverage of the 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Jane Petro and Bob Cabaj of AAPHR, and a medical student named Clarissa Kripke are interviewed. Kate O'Hanlan speaks.
      7. Damien Corboy is interviewed about the House of Representatives.
      8. The Lambda Update: Gay and lesbian adoption is covered. Beatrice Dohrn is interviewed.
      9. Wigstock 94 is covered.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 37 [Air date: 9/15/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0419 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0419)
      1. GCN's Coverage of the 1994 Primaries. Lee Sharmat and Damien Corby report. Mario Cuomo speaks and is interviewed about the gay and lesbian civil rights bill. The Attorney General race is covered from Karen Burstein's HQ. Burstein makes a speech. Catherine Aboti, newly elected state senator, is interviewed. Tom Duane speaks after losing his congressional run. Chris Quinn, campaign manager, political analyst Bob Bailey, and Jerry Nadler are interviewed.
      2. News Notes: 60 Minutes interviews Bob McFarlane, former advisor to Reagan, who calls Oliver North a 'degenerate liar'. Shannon Faulkner, student at The Citadel, is covered. African-American women 15 times more likely to have AIDS than white women. Gay students are being assaulted in Washington state schools and few reports have been filed because the abuse is so routine for gay and lesbian students. Forced HIV testing being considered in Russia. OJ Simpson gossip. OutLoud is announced. California governor Pete Wilson vetoes domestic partners law. Humm and Sharmat discuss Priscilla: Queen of the Desert.
      3. Gabriel Rotello interviewed about his controversial Newsday piece about AIDS and the gay community. In a follow-up, Michelangelo Signorelli discusses his column in Out Magazine with a similar theme.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Parade, a very mainstream family-oriented Sunday news magazine, covers gay and lesbian parents, and interviews kids with gay and lesbian parents. Viewers are encouraged to write to Parade, which Parade actively encourages.
      COMMERCIAL: Black and Blue Ball in Montreal, Tour Du Jour.
      6. Lavender Health: Further coverage of the 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Walt Odets, a clinical psychologist, speaks. Marj Plumb, lesbian health policy advocate also speaks.
      COMMERCIAL: Urad Leather Cream ("You can treat me bad… but you gotta treat your leather right.")
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 38 [Air date: 9/22/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0420 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0420)
      1. News Notes: Michael Feinstein comes out of the closet, complete with cover interview on The Advocate. AIDS fundraiser at the Playboy mansion. More organizations pulling events out of Cobb County in Georgia. Division of AIDS Services is saved in New York. Richard Dreyfuss directing version of Hamlet with a lesbian Ophelia and Gertrude, leading to one actress leaving the play. Woman who was fired from Dallas police force for being a lesbian wins lawsuit against city, leading to hiring policy changes. Gay and lesbian themed films and TV are discussed, including the film version of Jeffery and Harvey Firestein's sitcom on CBS. GLAAD goes national.
      2. Analysis of the primaries. Lee Sharmat, Andy Humm, Damien Corby, and David Blanton discuss the primaries.
      3. The Lambda Update: Denny Lee introduces this segment on Lambda's work on the Non-Discrimination Act. Evan Wolfson is interviewed.
      4. GLAAD Media Alert: Gay characters on Melrose Place causing headaches at Fox, with episodes being toned down due to 'economics'; My So-Called Life on ABC features a recurring bisexual character. The Brady Bunch Movie may feature a lesbian character. Viewers are encouraged to write to Paramount Pictures.
      5. Lavender Health: 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Safe sex for lesbians. Amber Hollibaugh, Laura Ramos, Rochelle Burroughs, and Ana L. Oliveira speak.
      COMMERCIAL: Poz Magazine
      6. Stonewall exhibit at the NYPL. Lou Maletta reports on Becoming Visible: The Legacy of Stonewall. (this is a re-airing of an earlier segment)
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 39 [Air date: 9/29/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0421 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0421)
      1. News Notes: First gay pride parade in Tokyo attracts mostly lesbians. Australia has eliminated all but one sodomy law. Mississippi high school cancels gay-themed play. Cuba has camps for people with HIV. The number for No on 13, a protest on anti-gay legislation in Oregon is displayed.
      2. Bob and Rod. Leonard Rosenblatt interviews Rod Jackson and Bob Paris, authors of Bob and Rod.
      COMMERCIAL: GMHC Presents Angels on Ice
      3. David Blanton interviews Gerardo Ramirez of the Log Cabin Club in New York, who is encouraging gays to vote Republican.
      4. GLAAD Media Alert: NBC Nightly News runs a series Gay in America. Viewers are encouraged to write to NBC. A few clips are shown.
      COMMERCIAL: AIDS Walk Long Island
      5. Lavender Health: Tuberculosis short PSA. Thomas Freeden of the New York City Bureau of Tuberculosis Control.
      6. Mr. Drummer 1994. Leather event in San Francisco.
      COMMERCIAL: Support Human Rights for Lesbian and Gay People.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 40 [Air date: 10/6/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0422 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0422)
      1. News Notes: Gay-bashing in Wisconsin. Scandal in France over blood supplied to hemophiliacs in 1985; instead of getting an American blood testing kit, the French waited an entire year until a French company developed a blood testing kit. During this time approx. 1,200 people were infected with HIV. Rueben Diaz controversy continues. In Phoenix, a gay couple's home is vandalized, and it takes 8 hours for police to respond. Jay Severin says to feminists who are angry that Pataki is not pro choice: "Fuck those fucking lesbian communists. They don't get to define pro-choice." Damien Corby reports that 67% of those polled in Ireland support gay marriage.
      2. The Da Da Ball at Webster Hall. Garth Clark and Mark del Vecchio are interviewed. Tippi Hedren will introduce the event.
      3. Phone interview with Julie Davis of No on 13 in Oregon. Davis and others, including Oregon's governor, are trying to defeat anti-gay legislation.
      4. Carmen Vasquez from the Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center announces a voter registration drive.
      5. OutLoud Expo at Pier 92. Roz Winter, organizer, is interviewed.
      6. Ann Northrop is interviewed about the current state of gay rights organizations.
      7. GLAAD Media Alert: Snapple sponsors Rush Limbaugh's show, in spite of Snapple's anti-discrimination policies. Viewers are encouraged to write to Snapple and encourage them to pull their sponsorship.
      8. Lavender Health: Victoria H. Raveis is interviewed.
      9. The Lambda Update: Barry Taylor is interviewed about the Americans With Disabilities Act.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 41 [Air date: 10/13/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0423 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0423)
      1. News Notes: Reporting from Coming Out Day at Christopher Street. Guy Molinari states Karen Burstein, Democratic nominee for Attorney General in New York, was not qualified for the job because she is an open lesbian. Helms' anti-gay bill is defeated. James Jennings in convicted. 40% of attempts to censor curricula in schools succeeded in the past year. Rueben Diaz gets a pitcher of water thrown at him.
      2. Lou Maletta reports from the Dada Ball. Some very elaborate costumes are showcased.
      3. Gay and Lesbian Business Expo '94, also known as Outloud. Linda Grishman, Mikel of the G Mikel Salon, James E. Law of IDS Financial Services, and Philip the editor of Uncommon Heroes.
      4. Black and Blue Ball in Montreal. Dale Hogan and Jay Henry report. Partygoers are interviewed.
      5. Empire State Pride Agenda annual gala. Dick Gottfreid, Alan Hevesi, Vivian Shapiro, Gabriel Rotello of Newsday, Francis Kunreuther, Karen Burstein, Mario Cuomo, and Mark Green are interviewed. Charles Millard refuses to be interviewed. Mario Cuomo gives a speech.
      6. Lavender Health: Gabriel A. Torres discusses cryptosporidium being found in New York City drinking water.
      7. GLAAD Media Alert: Guy Molinari's homophobic statements about Karen Burstein are covered. GLAAD is calling for Molinari's immediate dismissal.
      COMMERCIAL: Suave Succubus at the Wings Theater
      8. Guy Molinari's anti-gay comments are shown. The Anti-Violence Project is holding a protest; Ed Sedarbaum announces the logistics.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 42 [Air date: 10/20/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0424 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0424)
      1. News Notes: Robert Kase shot in a gay cruising area. Viewers who have been harassed are encouraged to call the Anti-Violence Project. Cobb County opens its first gay disco. Two male octopi having sex is taped by scientists. HGH can help people with AIDS. Two gay men murdered in Mississippi. The Magic Binoculars by Carmine Red is mentioned.
      2. Lou Maletta interviews Brad Kimmelman and Salvatore Moltisanti of Zuma Records.
      3. Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project goes to Long Island to protest Guy Molinari. H. Carl McCall is interviewed. It is revealed that Molinari is anti-abortion even though his wife recently had an abortion. Jimmy Breslin reports that a former Molinari aide has stated Molinari's anti-gay remarks were to get back at his gay brother.
      4. Lou Maletta and Joe Manto, a specialist in water treatment, discuss cryptosporidium.
      COMMERCIAL: Professional Plumbing, Specialists in Water Treatment Systems.